德怀特·曼菲雷迪 外号将军
CHICKIE: Dwight "The General" Manfredi.
前情提要
我想让你去塔尔萨
Tulsa, I want you to go there.
真的吗
Are you serious?
我为你们家做了这么多
After everything I've done for this family.
你不懂帮派怎么做事
You don't understand how this fucking works.
我不懂
I don't understand?
看在以前的情分上 我就不计较了
But I'm gonna overlook this for old time's sake.
一开始你每周上交五千
You'll kick up five grand a week to start.
我叫泰森 欢迎来到塔尔萨
Name's Tyson. Welcome to Tulsa.
去哪儿
Where to?
今后这么办
DWIGHT: This is how it's gonna work--
你负责赚钱 我负责帮你守住钱
you make the money and I make sure you keep it.
-我有的选吗  -当然没有
- Do I have a choice? - Absolutely not.
今后你就是我司机
You drive for me now.
是我喜欢的黑帮调调
My gangsta, ha-ha!
-对了 我叫米奇  -德怀特
- I'm Mitch, by the way. - Dwight.
我们本来要请你参加派对的
We're gonna invite you to the party.
那应该算不上派对吧
I wouldn't really call that a party.
那你说什么才算派对
What do you call a party?
-我玩的很开心  -还能再见吗
- I had a good time. - Maybe I'll see you around.
一个黑手党高层头目
A high-ranking Mafia capo who has decided
决定来塔尔萨焕发事业第二春
to grace Tulsa with his presence.
真是操了
Oh, fuck me.
亲爱的爸爸 这张钞票是我的零花钱
用它买个礼物吧 我想你 爱你
蒂娜
梅奥酒店
克里斯蒂娜·蔓菲雷迪          32                   纽约
快速寻找失散的亲人
克里斯蒂娜·蔓菲雷迪-格里格       曾用名：克里斯蒂娜·蔓菲雷迪
年龄:32   居住地：纽约            已知家庭成员：6人
请输入您的信用卡信息
优惠价解锁所有信息
给你
MAN: There you are.
-你好吗  -你好
- How you doing? - Good.
这个我想连夜寄到纽约
I need to send this to New York overnight.
有易腐物品 锂电池
And any perishables, lithium batteries,
易燃液体或枪支吗
flammable liquids or firearms?
这里面吗 没有
In the box? Nah.
价格为28.32美元
Looks like it'll be $28.32.
-维萨卡还是万事达卡  -现金
- Visa or Mastercard? - Cash.
我们已经不接受现金了
Yeah, we don't accept cash anymore.
我必须要问一句
You know, not for nothing,
我知道规矩不是你们定的
and I know you don't make the rules--
但这世界到底怎么了
what the fuck is going on with the world, huh?
现金为王 你听过这个说法吗
Cash is king. You ever hear that expression?
-没听过 抱歉  -多好的一句话
- No, I'm sorry. - It's a great expression.
抱歉先生 我信用卡忘酒店了
Excuse me, sir, I forgot my credit cards
想问一下
back at the hotel, and I was wondering,
能不能我把现金给你 你帮我刷下卡
if I give you cash, could you put it on your card?
没问题
Sure.
真是我的大英雄
You're a freaking hero.
德怀特的双份浓缩
WOMAN: Dwight? Double espresso?
请问 你们这没有玻璃咖啡杯吗
Young lady, do you have a glass coffee cup?
您真环保 但我们已经不提供玻璃杯了
Super cool you're green, but we don't use glass anymore.
连个正经杯子都没了
So, no real cups no more?
很抱歉
Sorry.
德怀特·大卫·曼菲雷迪
GIBSON: Dwight David Manfredi.
1947年7月出生于纽约布鲁克林
Born Brooklyn, New York, July 1947.
西西里黑帮的长期成员
Long-time member of Cosa nostra,
科萨诺斯塔：西西里黑手党，简称黑手党，其成员经常称其为Cosa nostra
初代美国人
first-generation American,
老爸是理发师 老妈是家庭主妇
dad was a barber, mom, a homemaker.
-有子女吗  -有个女儿 克里斯蒂娜 30出头
- Any kids? - Daughter Cristina, early 30s.
-没查到前妻信息  -行吧
- Nothing on the ex-wife. - Okay.
你查这个干什么
Can I ask what you need this for?
有线报说他来塔尔萨了 我跟进一下
We got a tip that he's in town, so, you know, following up.
-得了吧亲爱的  -怎么了
- Honey, please. - What?
咱俩都认识多久了
How long do we know each other?
他请我喝了一杯 啥也没发生
He bought me a drink. Nothing happened.
-他请你喝了一杯  -对
- He bought you a drink? - Yeah.
披头士红起来之前他就有犯罪记录了
I got a rap sheet in front of me goes back to before the Beatles,
包括两起谋杀
including two murders.
我刚说 我俩啥都没干 好吗
I just said nothing happened, okay?
他都杀了谁
Who'd he kill?
第一个叫理查德·麦克利维 代号离谱
First, a guy named Richard McLeevy, aka Ripple.
第二个是在监狱自卫时杀的
Second, a self-defense in prison.
-嗯  -怎么了
- Huh. - What?
警方前后做过他6次思想工作
They tried to flip him six different times.
他愣是没开口 选择坐牢25年
Did a 25-year stretch rather than talk.
这一点值得敬佩
Well, you gotta admire that, right?
真的吗 他可是混黑帮的
Do you? He's a fucking gangster.
我只是说 至少他够有种
I'm just saying, at least he's got some integrity.
就是这种冷峻还有底线的杀手
Nothing sexier than a cold-blooded killer
最容易让人沦陷
with principles.
下次我过去咱俩见一面
I'll see you next time I'm in town.
谢谢了
Thank you.
您已越线 请等待
VOICE: Wait.
请等待
Wait.
我都等一辈子了
Been waiting my whole life.
请等待
Wait.
真是难以置信
WOMAN: Can you believe that?
宇宙的中心
WOMAN: Center of the universe!
原来如此啊
Is that what this is?
也不是 只不过大家都这么叫
Not really, it's just what they call it.
你站进那个圆圈
- Oh. - You stand in that circle,
外面的人就听不到你讲话
and nobody outside it can hear a sound.
-不会吧  -不信你试试
- No shit? - Try it.
我要说什么
What do I say?
啥都行 反正我也听不见
It won't matter, I won't be able to hear you anyway.
好吧
All right.
马
Horse.
喂 你听到了吗
Hey, did you hear that?
听到我说什么了吗
Did you hear that?
我都说了 里面啥也听不到
I told you, nobody can hear anything.
那是跟上帝说知心话的地方
People talk to God in there.
等等
Hold up.
给你
Here you go.
为啥
What's that?
给自己买点好吃的
Get yourself something good to eat.
我才不要你的脏钱
I don't want any of your scuzzy money.
所以 最近状态怎么样
So, how goes the battle?
时好时坏的
Good days, bad days.
酗酒的问题呢
How's the drinking?
不错 我觉得自己控制住了
Really good. I think I am nailing that.
爱德华呢
Edward?
-你俩有联系吗  -不太联系
- You guys talking? - Not much.
他开始约会别人了
He's...he's dating a lady.
你自己呢
How 'bout you?
这都一年多了 也该重新约会了
Been over a year. You're entitled.
但我不会称其为约会
I wouldn't say that I'm dating anyone.
有跟人睡过吗
Slept with someone?
睡过
Yep. I did.
-他人怎么样  -年纪挺大
- What was he like? - Old.
-多大  -真的很老了
- How old? - Really fucking old.
他75了
Like, he's 75.
他还是个罪犯
And he's also a criminal.
你打算再跟他约吗
Are you planning on seeing him again?
不 没打算
No. I'm not.
好 那就好
Okay. Good.
哟 来了 感觉如何
There he is. How you feeling?
下颌骨断了三处
Fucking mandible's broke in three places.
-抱歉了 兄弟  -这就完了
- Sorry, bro. - That's it?
就用这话来搪塞我
That's all you gotta say?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我可是有头有脸的人 我就这意思
I'm a made fucking guy, that's what I mean!
我是个黑帮首领
A fucking capo!
你想让我做什么
What do you want me to do?
-去你妈的 齐齐  -喂
- Fucking bullshit, Chickie! - Hey.
-这傻叉  -别激动
- This cock... - Calm the fuck down.
别弄伤自己
You're gonna get hurt.
这傻逼先动手的
This fucking cocksucker raised his hands.
所以你什么诉求
So, what do you wanna do?
-你想杀了他吗  -对
- You wanna kill the guy? - Yeah.
你他妈以为呢
The fuck you think?
他是我爸朋友 你知道的 文斯
My dad's friend, Vince. You know that.
他也是个首领
And he's a capo too.
咱们家族到底讲不讲规矩了
Do we got rules in this family or not?
当然讲
Of course we do.
行吧 我跟我老爸谈谈的
All right. I'll talk to my father.
谢谢
Thank you.
你不上车吗
You getting in?
一周付你两千块
You would think for two grand a week,
期待着你下车开个车门呢
you'd get out and open the door.
真的吗 你真想让我干这种事
Seriously? You want me to do that shit?
倒也不是
No.
但你主动做就会很暖心
But it would have been nice if you offered.
所以咱去哪儿 老大
So, where to, boss?
我得弄张信用卡
I need a credit card.
合法的还是非法的
Like a legal one, or a fugazi?
-合法的  -那你得填个申请表
No, legal. - Well, you need to fill out
还得提供收入证明
an application and shit, and show some income.
但我提供不了 对吧
Well, can't really do that, can I?
先弄张借记卡吧 也一样用
Well, you can get a debit card, it's just as good.
-怎么申请  -先去银行
- How's that work? - You go to the bank
填一堆文件
and you, uh...fill out some paperwork,
往里面存点钱 就会得到一张卡
and deposit some cash, and they give you a card.
这不就回答你的问题了吗
Well, there's the answer to your question.
-我的什么问题  -老大咱去哪儿的问题
- To what question? - "Where to, boss?"
先去菩提那儿拿点钱
Let's go see Bodhi so I can get some cash.
这货真带劲儿
Oh, shit's fire.
葡萄奶昔味道刚刚好
Ooh, that Grape Milkshake slaps.
扫兴鬼来了
And buzzkill.
这才早上11点
The fact that it's barely 11:00 a.m.
你就把客人叫做扫兴鬼
and you got a buzz to kill
真让我质疑你的工作态度
makes me question your work ethic.
我是卖大麻的 不是搞核反应堆的
I'm selling weed, not operating a nuclear reactor.
-早啊 弗雷德  -早
- Morning, Fred. - Morning.
另外 再敢叫我扫兴鬼
Second of all, call me buzzkill again,
我就给你的肾换换地方
I will rearrange your kidneys.
-好吧  -我需要用钱
- Yeah. - I need some money.
早啊 小鬼
Morning, Spooky.
你这打扮也太没新意了 哥们
That's some real cornball stuff right there, man.
-什么  -一头脏辫
- What? - The dreads.
不知道踩了多少
There's a lot of cultural appropriation
文化挪用的雷
going on in here.
冒着被您重新安排器官
So, at the risk of you rearranging my internal organs
或其他酷刑的风险 我还是要问问
or some other creative way of inflicting pain,
你从我这儿拿钱有啥计划吗
is there some sort of structure to you taking my money?
每周就拿两成
It's 20% a week.
抱歉 但我能从中得到什么
I'm sorry, what do I get out of this?
这点你从没提过
'Cause I'm still missing that.
问题是你没得到应得的东西
It's what you're not getting, which is hosed.
说到这 我得跟你的供应商聊聊
Speaking of which, I need to talk to your supplier.
-吉米吗  -对
- Jimmy? - Yeah.
-为啥  -我想谈个更低的拿货价
- Why? - So I can cut a better deal.
对了 我给咱们找了一个新的投资线
And by the way, I got a line on a new investment for us.
应该很快就能赚到钱
We'll be making money hand over fist,
而且联调局也奈何不了我们
and the Feds won't be able to touch it.
所以你说的这些啥时候开始
When will all of this start happening?
作为一个早上11点就开始飞叶子的人
You know, for a guy that's stoned at 11:00 in the morning,
你也太他妈没耐心了
you're pretty freaking impatient.
好了 现居住地
Okay, and current address?
梅奥酒店
Mayo Hotel.
没有长期居住地址吗
Do you have a permanent residence?
-同一个地方  -具体位置呢
- Same place. - And where's that located?
-到你了  -西 西五
- You're on. - West-West Fifth...
西五大街115号
115 West Fifth.
好的 能看下身份证明吗
Okay, I'll just need to see some ID.
纽约 我去过一次
New York. I've been there once.
时代广场
Times Square.
带护照了吗
Do you happen to have a passport?
最近没怎么旅行 所以没带
I haven't been doing a lot of traveling lately.
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
这个恐怕不行 过期了
I can't accept this. It's expired.
我又不是来找你借车的
Look, I don't wanna borrow your car.
你不是要看身份证明吗
You asked for ID.
我知道 但这个1998年就过期了
I know, it's just, it expired in 1998.
人们之所以会违法
This is why people break the law,
是因为他们把所有合法的事
because they make everything legitimate
都搞得特别复杂
so freaking complicated.
也没那么复杂吧
It ain't all that complicated,
我们给你弄个新驾照就行
we just get you a new license.
你是个好市民嘛
You're such a good citizen.
-能问你个问题吗  -问吧
- Can I ask you a question? - Sure.
你为什么进拘留所了
Why'd you go to jail?
我不是进拘留所 我是坐牢了
I didn't go to jail, I went to prison.
拘留所那是坐牢之前
Jail's like a five-star resort they put you in
送你进去等候的五星场所
before they send you to prison.
那你到底干什么了
So, what'd you do?
有个家伙不停问我白痴问题
I tore the tongue out of this guy
我把他舌头给割下来了
who kept asking so many stupid questions.
这有点过了吧 你不觉得吗
It's a bit excessive, don't you think?
有心了
I'm impressed.
红袜队6胜6负 洋基队6胜7负
MANNY: Red Sox are even 6, Yanks are 6 to 7.
芬纳里奥牧场
-亚特兰大勇士呢  -9-11
MAN: How 'bout the Braves? - 9-11.
-买两注亚特兰大勇士  -没问题
- Put two on the Braves. - You got it.
明天赢钱的时候我就回来了
I'll be back tomorrow when I win.
我就在这等你
Yeah, I'll be waiting right here.
曼尼 有电话
Manny? Got a call.
谢了 罗克西
Oh, thanks, Roxy.
我是曼尼
This is Manny. EDDIE:
曼尼是犹太人裁缝的名字
Manny's the name for a Jew tailor.
你查到什么了 艾迪
What do you got for me, Eddie?
你说对了 就是他
You're right. It's him.
-是艾克  -草
- It's Ike. - Fuck me.
我就知道
I knew it.
-他来这干什么  -那我就不知道了
- What's he doing here? - That, I don't know.
还有啥好问的 他肯定是来弄死我的
Oh, who am I kidding? He's here to fucking kill me.
也许就是来度个假呢
Maybe he's on vacation.
是啊 巴哈马群岛都订满了是吧
Yeah, yeah, and the Bahamas were probably booked.
他住哪
Where's he staying?
这边有几个好酒店啊
How many nice hotels you got down there?
不知道 就一个
I don't know, one?
那就去那查呗 煞笔
Then maybe look there, stunad.
草泥马啊 谢了
Fuck you. And thanks.
俄克拉荷马驾照考试
脸朝前
MAN: Face front, please.
先生 您这是干什么
Sir, what are you doing?
下一个
Next in line.
下午好
Good afternoon.
你需要参加路考
You're gonna need to take a road test.
我从13岁就开车了
I've been driving since I was 13.
这是规定
Those are the rules.
下一个可预约的时间是
Next appointment is in...
5周后
in five weeks.
好奇怪
Well, this is strange.
好像下周初空出来一个位置
Looks like there's an opening early next week.
这是学习许可 你可以用它来练习
That's a learner's permit. You can use that to practice.
这玩意儿能当身份证用吗
Is this good for ID?
这跟普通驾照一样
It's just like a regular license.
都完事了 我给你们申请的特快流程
And we're all set. I put a rush on it.
你在24到48小时之内就能收到
You should receive your new debit card
新的借记卡了
within 24 to 48 hours.
如果你需要附属卡给你的
And if you need an extra card for your...
-同事  -同事
Colleague. - Colleague.
这年头身份不好瞎猜的
One can never assume these days.
随便猜 我为他打工的
Assume all you want. I work for him.
-没错  -谢谢你们
- That's true. - Well, thank you
选择塔尔萨银行
for choosing the Bank of Tulsa.
他以为咱俩是
Did he think we was...
我觉得是
I think so.
喂
Yeah?
你好啊 齐齐
How you doing, Chickie?
-塔尔萨待得好吗  -开什么玩笑
- How's Tulsa treating you? - Are you kidding me?
简直就是西南小巴黎
It's like the Paris of the Southwest.
这就对了 就得这么想
There you go, that's the spirit.
你老爹怎么样
So, how's your old man?
好着呢 就在我身边
He's good, he's here with me now.
-齐齐 替我问好  -没问题
- Chickie, send him my love. - Yeah, of course.
听着 我得跟你谈谈
So listen, I gotta talk to you.
文斯那事
That thing with Vince.
-啥事  -不是吧
What thing? - Seriously?
跟我装傻是吗
You're gonna play Mickey the Dunce?
我跟你说哈 齐齐
Let me tell you something, Chickie.
如果说有谁自找被人打掉下巴
If there was ever a guy that had a crack in the jaw
那就是他了
coming to him, it was that kid.
德怀特 他是个高层
Dwight, he's a made guy.
你跟他结下梁子了
You made a beef.
他想干啥 决斗吗
What's he want, a duel?
别这样 我们得理智点
Come on, we're rational people.
你这态度解决不了任何问题
That kinda shit don't solve anything.
你得想办法修补关系
But you gotta make amends.
行吧 那我给他写一张早日康复卡吧
All right, I'll get him a Get Well card.
德怀特 我认真的 他气坏了
Dwight, I'm serious. He's fucking pissed.
你得想办法解决这事
You gotta make this right.
你有啥好建议
And how do you suggest I do that?
10万块应该就行
100 grand would do it.
-开什么玩笑  -德怀特 这是行价
- Are you kidding me? - Dwight, it's a tax.
他下巴缝了针 说话都费劲
His jaw's wired shut, he can barely talk.
我没找你要钱就不错了
Then you ought to be paying me.
你害他难堪了 他疼得不行
You embarrassed him. He's in pain.
德怀特 这事你必须得解决
Dwight, you gotta make this go away.
-10万块就能解决  -对
- And 100 grand will do that? - Yes.
好吧 那我给他寄个东西过去
All right, I'll send him something.
但你要是听见里面有滴答声 可千万别打开
But if you hear it ticking, don't open it.
有人吗
STACY: Hello?
好了 好了 好了
Okay, okay, okay.
-谁啊  -史黛西·比尔
- Who is it? - It's Stacy Beale.
-谁  -我们前几晚见过
- Who? - We met a few nights ago.
不是吧
No.
-你好啊  -人们叫你德怀特是吗
- How you doing? - Do people call you Dwight?
我也该这么称呼你吗
Is that what I should call you?
没问题 要进来吗
Sure. Do you wanna come in?
好啊
Sure.
很高兴见到你
Really good seeing you.
-我只是想来跟你聊聊  -好
- I just wanted to talk to you. - Sure.
ATF：美国烟酒枪炮及爆炸物管理局
我是烟火枪炮管理局的探员
I'm an ATF agent.
前几晚就该告诉你的
I should have told you the other night,
但是没机会
but it didn't come up.
当重罪犯更换居住地时
You know, when high-level felons relocate,
联调局会发通告
the FBI sends out a bulletin.
你的照片被传到了我办公室
Your picture came through my office.
-我是前重罪犯  -很好
- I'm an ex-felon. - Great.
那一个前重罪犯 前黑手党头目
What's an ex-felon, former Mafia capo
来塔尔萨干嘛呢
doing in Tulsa?
如果你要是以公职身份来的
Maybe if you're here in your official capacity,
那我只能说不关你事了
maybe it's none of your business.
你来这你家人怎么看
What does your family think about you being here?
我是个前重罪犯 这话还需要我说多少次
I'm an ex-felon, how many times do I have to say it?
不 不是你的黑帮家人
No, not your mob family.
你的真正家人 你女儿
Your real family. Your daughter.
我很久没见过蒂娜了
I haven't seen my daughter Tina--
我女儿叫蒂娜 但我想你应该知道了
that's her name, but I'm sure you already know that.
18年了 我没见过她 也没见过
I haven't seen her or the rest of my relatives
其他亲戚
in 18 years.
我被抓时她还是个孩子
It was hard for her to see me all locked up.
对她来说应该挺难的 所以我想 就别再打扰她了
She was only a kid, so I said, don't come back no more.
让她别那么痛苦
Save her the pain.
所以基本上 纽约对我来说没什么可留恋的
So basically, there's nothing left for me in New York.
所以你决定搬到塔尔萨来了
So, you just decided to move to Tulsa?
为什么不呢
Why not?
听着 我需要你知道 如果你在这遇到什么麻烦
Listen, I need you to know that if you get jammed up here,
我可帮不了你
there's nothing I can do to help you out.
没指望你帮我
I don't expect you to.
完事了吗 史黛西·比尔
We done, Stacy Beale?
约翰·刘易斯在埃德蒙·佩特斯桥上
You know, John Lewis didn't get his head broke
约翰·刘易斯：美国知名黑人民权运动领导者，1965年带抗议者穿过埃德蒙·佩特斯桥
展示黑人投票必要性时差点被警察殴打致死
被打到颅骨骨折
on the Edmund Pettus Bridge
可不是为了让你给黑帮分子洗林肯车的
so you could spit-shine some gangster's Lincoln.
你说的对
Oh, you right about that.
他那么做是为了让你去给白人通马桶的
He did it so you can unplug them white folks' toilets.
你最好是开玩笑
You better be smiling.
我像你这么大时都开始养家糊口了
When I was your age, I had mouths to feed.
我知道 爸 我就 我就是开玩笑呢嘛
I know, Dad, I'm just-- I'm just kidding.
你应该去上大学
You should be in college.
爸 别这样 大清早的又要开始说教吗
Come on, Dad, we gonna do this this early in the morning?
那家伙是个商人 我可以跟他学到不少东西
Dude a businessman, you know, I can learn a lot from him.
拉里
Larry!
搞特么啥啊伙计
What the hell, man?
你的狗在我的草坪上拉屎
Your dog crapped on my lawn.
你怎么知道是我的狗
How do you know it was my dog?
因为我看见了
Because I just saw him.
对草有好处 肥料呢
Good for the grass. Fertilizer.
那你让他给你草坪施肥啊
Well, let him fertilize your grass, huh?
就这样吗
That's it?
那么 这家伙叫什么来着
So, what's this guy's name again?
吉米 克里克印第安人
Jimmy. Creek Indian.
克里克吉米 这名字逗了
Jimmy the Creek? That's rich.
等你见过他表亲刀疤脸再说
Wait till you meet his cousin Bad Face.
说到部落中人
Speaking of members of the Tribe,
我看到你的种植者证上写着
I read the name on your grower's license.
劳伦斯·盖德曼
Lawrence Geigerman?
这是你的真名
That's your name?
你们这是什么反犹太团伙吗
Are we on some anti-Semitic tip now?
怎么会 我喜欢犹太人 喜欢犹太族食物
No, come on, I love the Jews. I love Jewish food.
你为啥要取个佛教菩提的绰号
So, what's with this Buddhist Bodhi bullshit nickname?
怎么 你们这行业就没绰号的吗
Come on, you never had a handle in your line of work?
他们通常怎么称呼你
What did they used to call you?
我的名字来自于德怀特·艾森豪威尔将军
I was named after General Dwight Eisenhower,
所以他们都叫我 五星
so they called me Cinque Stelle.
五星
Five Star.
菩提 我们这是在哪
Bodhi, where the hell are we?
抱歉给你造成不便
Sorry for the inconvenience,
但没有人把100英亩的种植田
but no one puts a 100-acre grow
和浓缩大麻实验室建在美国85号公路路边
and a shatter lab on the side of U.S. 85.
真好闻
Smells good.
你好啊 我叫德怀特
How you doing? I'm Dwight.
他是吉米表亲 疤脸
This is Jimmy's cousin, Bad Face.
要比谁盯的久是怎么着
This a staring contest?
你姓什么 白人佬
You got a last name, wasicu?
什么意思
What's that mean?
直译过来是指贪婪的偷肥肉的
Literal translation is a greedy non-Indian person
非印第安人
who steals the fat.
还是头一回听说
That's a first.
姓什么
You got a last name?
不说有意见么
You got a problem?
意见大了 王八犊子
I got serious problems, motherfucker.
行吧 这个开场白相当不愉快
Okay, so we got off to a really bad start here,
但我觉得还是可以斡旋的
but I think we can turn this around.
你骑过马吗
You ever been on a horse?
你用过生命维持机器吗
You ever been on life support?
等等等等
JIMMY: Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
嘿 别冲动 各位 别这样
Hey, take it easy, guys, come on!
-嘿 吉米  -别急眼
- Hey, Jimmy. - Easy, easy now.
没什么不愉快是上好大麻解决不了的
Nothing a little bit of the fine Chiba won't fix.
都不用穿桑拿服
DWIGHT: You don't even need a sauna suit.
也许我在不自知的情况下就下了地狱
Maybe I went to hell and I don't even know it.
自便
Help yourself.
谈判的时候我不飞叶子
I negotiate with a clear head.
这个就够了
I'll stick with this.
没谈判一说
There'll be no negotiating.
芽的话1200一个单位
It's $1,200 a unit for the buds
10单位起订
based on a 10-unit order.
咱们走 大麻农场多的是
Let's go. There's other weed farms.
而且 每单位我会附赠一箱宠物滴剂
And...I'll throw in a case each of CBD Doggie Droppers
和飞升贴合人体润滑剂
and Rapture Patch personal lubricant.
润滑剂
Lubricant?
价格方面再降点 吉米
You gotta do better on the price, Jimmy.
量大从优 你得付一大笔钱
But for the glut, you're gonna be paying over a deuce.
要想单价低于1200 除非买光剥夺品种的
You won't do better than $1,200 unless you're into DEPs.
光照不足 催熟品种
Light-deprived, forced ripe.
你想要多少单位
So, how many units you want?
你不介意的话 我也想问几个问题
I'll ask the questions, if you don't mind.
先说下 这个很好吃
This is delicious, by the way.
你经营这摊生意是纵向一体化的吗
So, is your operation vertically integrated?
你是种大麻的
You're a cultivator.
可你手上有催熟的 丁烷大麻油 提纯萃取装置 浓缩物
You got DEPs, BHO, CRC, blast concentrate.
是不是中转站我一眼就能看出来
I know a trans-shipment station when I see one.
所以你们占地多少
So, what do you got here?
500英亩 也许更多
500 acres? Maybe more?
说不定月球上都能瞧见这片地呢
Probably see this place from the fucking moon.
是挺大的
It's big.
大到你想把丰收之后留下的
Big enough that you wanna sell me bruised fruit
烂果卖给我 我还得
from your bumper crop, and I'm supposed to be touched
感恩戴德
by your generosity?
我要300单位
I'll take 300 units.
头10单位1200 之后10单位1100
$1,200 for the first 10 units, $1,100 for the next 10,
再然后的10个单位是1000
$1,000 for the 10 after that,
之后剩下的270个单位都按750的价格给我
and $750 each for the remaining 270 units.
我得算算
I'll have to do the math.
那就算快点儿 等我吃完这个饼干
Well, do it fast because the offer expires
报价就作废
when I swallow this cracker.
你还挺会讨价还价
You drive a hard bargain.
-但价格公道  -成交
- But fair. - Deal.
什么时候抽根讲和烟
When are we gonna smoke the peace pipe?
-有这必要么  -有
- Do we need to? - Yeah.
毕竟一开始我跟疤脸不大愉快
Me and Fuck Face got off to a bad start.
疤脸
Bad Face.
那事儿不好意思啊
And I'm sorry about that.
别逗了 他这种给我来10个都行
You kidding? I could use 10 like him.
对了 我应该跟你说
Mm, and...I should probably tell you.
你吃的那个杏仁酱
that apricot preserve you're eating?
很好吃
Perfecto.
里头掺了四氢大麻酚
It's infused with THC.
掺了多少
How infused?
相当多
Heavily, man.
这里可是大麻农场
It's a weed farm.
怪不得我感觉这么好呢
I was wondering why I was feeling so good.
靠
Gee.
-我尝个试试  -嘿
- Let me try one of these. - Hey.
至于么
Damn.
嘿 德怀特 上头了是么
Hey, Dwight, you feeling it?
有这可能
There's a possibility.
-来点儿不  -不了
- Want some? - No.
-好啦  -来点儿
- Okay. - Want some?
-给  -慢了
- Here. - Beep.
你是想再给抽走么
Are you just gonna pull it away again?
不会 当然不会啦 信我
No, of course not. Trust me.
-行吧  -拿不到
- Yeah. - Boop.
给你
Okay.
我也想你嗨一点
I want you to get a little nuts too.
烂柯人（Rip Van Winkle），民间故事人物，在野外睡了一觉，醒来后发现世间已过几十年
我感觉自己像是烂柯人
You know, I feel like Rip Van Winkle.
25年后醒来
You wake up after 25 years,
通用汽车公司开始搞电车 迪伦上市了
GM has gone electric, Dylan's gone public,
电话变成了照相机
a phone is a camera.
咖啡 竟然卖五块钱一杯
Coffee, five bucks a cup!
还有滚石乐队 上帝保佑他们
And the Stones, bless their heart,
-还在巡演  -真的吗
- they're still on tour. - Word?
这才叫音乐
Now that, that's music.
声音调大
Turn it up. Turn it up.
-声调大点 菩提  -我能理解
- Turn it up, Bodhi. - I understand,
但我也控制不了
but I don't have control over that.
-大脑转起来  -做不到
- Turning your brain up. - That won't do it.
我问你们件事啊
Let me ask you guys something.
说真的 很严肃的问
Seriously, I mean, seriously...
现在这个国家
what's going on with this country
到底是怎么回事
in general nowadays?
就你们这一代人 好好说说
I mean, like, your generation, seriously, come on.
还有这些代词
And these pronouns,
这些代词都几个意思
what the fuck is with the pronouns?
他 她 他 他们 它 一堆有的没的
He, she, him, they, the, boom, bang, ba, fa, foo.
你知道我的代词是什么吗 猜猜看
You know what my pronoun is? Guess.
时间到 是它
- Uh... - Time's up. "It."
就是 它再也受不了这堆狗屁玩意儿的那个它
As in, it can't take this shit anymore.
我是支持改变的 真的
I'm all for change, I am. I really am.
但就是有人一直不停试探底线
But somebody keeps moving the goalposts.
我小时候 在我住的那片
When I was a kid, in my neighborhood,
最起码我是知道我是谁的
at least I knew who I was.
或者说我觉得我是知道的
Or I thought I did.
但讲真 谁又能什么都懂
But truthfully, nobody knows nothing.
你住的那片有兄弟吗 老炮儿
You had any brothers in your neighborhood, OG?
我还没说完呢
I'm not done.
你有听说过阿瑟·米勒吗 那个剧作家
Did you ever hear of Arthur Miller, the playwright?
你们肯定没听说过 我想啥呢
Of course, you haven't, what am I doing?
阿瑟·米勒写过一部剧说的就是我住的那边
Arthur Miller wrote a play about my neighborhood
叫《桥上的风景》
called "View From the Bridge."
不是亨利·米勒
Not Henry Miller.
亨利·米勒写的是《北回归线》
Henry Miller wrote "Tropic of Cancer."
写的还成 算是能看
Which was okay, not bad.
但亚瑟·米勒 可是跟
But Arthur Miller, who banged, whacked,
玛丽莲梦露天雷勾地火 床上大战三百回合
tick-tapped, double-whap-packed Marilyn Monroe,
然后还娶了她 还赢了那个普利策奖
and married her, and won the freaking Pulitzer Prize.
但在我看来 他每晚
But in my opinion, him getting to bang
跟玛丽莲梦露颠鸾倒凤
and sleep nightly with Marilyn Monroe
才是迄今为止他得到的最牛逼的奖项
is by far his greatest triumph.
这玩意儿够劲儿
Wow, this stuff is potent.
-梅奥酒店  -你好
MAN: Mayo Hotel. - Yeah, hi.
我想找个朋友
I'm looking for a friend,
他应该是住你们酒店
I believe he's staying at your hotel.
请问住客姓名
Name of the guest, please?
曼菲雷迪
Manfredi.
好的 请稍等
Okay, just one sec.
不好意思先生 这里没有客人叫这个名字
I'm sorry, sir, there's no one here under that name.
那艾克呢 能查到艾克吗
How 'bout an Ike? You got an Ike?
-请问是名字吗  -德怀特
- Is that a first name? - Dwight.
曼斯先生啊
Oh, Mr. Manse.
纽约过来的对不对
From New York, right?
没错没错 就是他
Yeah, that that's right. That's him.
请稍等 我帮您转接
Okay, hold on. I'll connect you.
不用不用 是这样 我这边有人来
No, no, you know what? Somebody just walked in.
回头我给你打过去好吧
I'm gonna have to call you back, okay?
没问题 谢谢您 先生
Sounds good. Thank you, sir.
客气 谢了
Sure thing. Thanks.
先生
MAN: Sir?
-这是给您的  -哦好
- This came for you. - Oh, right.
请输入您的信用卡信息
优惠价解锁所有信息
信用卡信息
卡片上名字                            卡号                                 邮编                   安全码
德怀特·蔓菲雷迪
解锁完整报告只需9.99美元
继续支付
克里斯蒂娜·蔓菲雷迪-格里格
曾用名
电话
已知亲属
年龄                      出生日期
居住地：        纽约
地址：           纽约
喂
MAN: Hello?
你好 请问蒂娜在吗
Hi, is Tina there?
请问您是
Who's this?
-她父亲  -什么
- It's her father. - What?
我是德怀特·曼菲雷迪 她父亲
It's Dwight Manfredi, it's her father.
请问你是哪位
Can I ask who this is?
我是她丈夫埃默里 稍等
I'm her husband, Emory. Hold on.
不好意思 她 她不想跟你说话
Listen, I'm sorry, but she-- she doesn't want to talk to you.
那边是你们孩子吗 你跟蒂娜生的
Are those your kids? Yours and Tina's?
孩子们别闹 我打电话呢
Guys, be quiet. I'm on the phone.
你刚说什么
What's that?
能麻烦你跟她说下我想听听她声音吗
Um, can you just tell her I wanna hear her voice?
等下
Hold on.
-喂  -蒂娜
TINA: Hello. Tina.
-你想听我声音  -是
You wanted to hear my voice. - Yeah.
听到了 满意了
There. You happy?
我能见见你吗
Can I see you?
请等待
VOICE: Wait. Wait.
我不再见她
I stopped seeing her...
因为对她来说太难了
because it was too hard on her.
不是
No.
我不再见她
I stopped seeing her...
因为对我来说太难了
because it was too hard on me.
我爱你
I love you.
我放弃了你
I quit on you.
对不起
And I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
对不起
-我们做到了  -给你带了瓶巴罗洛
- We made it. - Got you some Barolo.
我们在喝笑气
We're on nitrous, dude!
有人倒下了
Man down.
下集预告
五年后你要在哪儿见我
Where do you see me in five years?
你知道我是个罪犯对吧
You realize I'm a criminal, right?
我有个大师
I got a guru.
我不是来害你没命的
I'm not here to get you killed.
趴下
Down!
我差点被开枪杀死 却要起诉我
Am I being charged with almost getting shot?
我可不觉得这算是犯罪
'Cause I don't think that's a crime,
即便是在俄克拉荷马州也不算
even in Oklahoma.
有人想杀找
Somebody tried to kill me.
谁想要你命
WOMAN: Who might want you dead?